smilehouse.com 2017-02-27

# Tieto website privacy statement

The term “personal data”, as used in this Privacy Statement, refers to any information about you which can be used to personally identify you, such as your name, address, telephone number, e-mail address, or any other personal information you might supply.

Please read this Privacy Statement carefully prior to accessing the Website. If you do not agree with the terms of our Privacy Statement, please do not provide us with personal data and leave the Website.

## Personal data

Tieto processes your personal data in accordance with the [EC Data Protection Directive 95/46/EC](http://eur-lex.europa.eu/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31995L0046:EN:HTML) and the national personal data legislation implementing the directive.

### What personal information does Tieto collect?

Our primary goal in collecting information is to provide you with a friendly, customised and efficient experience. We collect the following types of information:

#### Information you volunteer to us

Tieto collects identifying information when you use the Website (including, but not limited to, any Tieto landing page). For example, we may require customers who use the Website to provide us with personal data such as their name, company name, address, phone number, and e-mail address.

We may also ask for additional types of personal data, such as your title, department name, or other additional information in order to provide you with a more personalised experience. Information that you provide to us will be kept as a record of your interaction with our Website.

#### Automatic information

When you visit our Website, Tieto collects your internet protocol (“IP”) addresses in order to track and aggregate non-personal information as you use the Website.

In addition, Tieto automatically receives and stores certain traffic data on our server logs, including your IP address, Tieto cookie information, your communication with Tieto and your interactions on the Website. Tieto uses this data only to diagnose technical problems, analyse trends and administer the Website.

## Purpose of processing

Personal data collected through the Website is processed for the purpose of

  * customer, investor and media relationship management and communication,
  * offering services on our Website,
  * providing marketing information via targeted e-mails or interpersonal communication
  * recruitment and human resource purposes
  * handling other matters related to the management and development of the Website and the services provided therein.

We will not hold it for any longer than legally permissible and necessary for these purposes.

## Transfer of personal data

Personal data may be transferred within the Tieto group of companies. Authorised third-party service providers may be used to process personal data on behalf of Tieto companies with respect to Tieto´s business needs. 

Personal data may be transferred to countries outside the EU or the EEA. Such transfers are conducted in accordance with the EC Data Protection Directive and the national personal data legislation implementing the directive. The model clauses approved by the European Commission form the basis for the transfer.

By submitting your personal data, you agree to this transfer, storing and processing. Tieto will take all reasonable steps necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this Privacy Statement.

Tieto reserves the right to transfer personal data when required by mandatory laws or authorities. Tieto may provide aggregate statistics about its customers, sales, traffic patterns, and other related Website information to third parties, but these statistics do not include personally identifiable data.

### Your rights

You have the right to know what personal data we hold about you. You may contact Tieto in order to review the accuracy of the personal data related to you. Upon your request, Tieto will rectify or delete any incomplete, inaccurate or outdated personal data.

You may withdraw your consent for processing of your personal data. As the processing of your personal data is necessary in order for us to be able to provide you with our services, revoking your consent may lead to a situation in which we cannot provide you with some or all of the services.

## Cookies and other tools

### Cookies

When you visit our Website, we may employ cookies that contain information (such as a unique cookie ID) used to track your usage of our Website. This enables our systems to recognise your browser and tell us how, when and which pages in our Website are visited and by how many people, and also enables us to recognise a return visitor as a unique user. Cookies placed by the Website cannot access, read or modify any other data on a computer.

Our Website may contain links to other websites and services which serve third-party cookies outside our control and are not covered by this Privacy Statement. You should review any privacy policies, services and applications found on such websites to understand how your information may be collected and used.

#### Marketing automation

The Website employs marketing automation programs from vendors operating on Tieto’s behalf, which use third-party cookies to track Website use.

When a user visits our Website, the cookie stores traffic data linked to the unique ID of the cookie in the browser. If the user identifies himself by volunteering personal data, e.g. by filling in a contact form or clicking on links in an e-mail sent by Tieto, the cookie’s unique user ID is linked to the personal data volunteered by the user.

This enables Tieto to supply a more personalised experience on its Website and in communications with customers and users of the Website. Tieto does not sell, rent or give away personal data that identifies individuals to any external party, except to parties who process data on Tieto’s behalf. By using this Website, you consent to the processing of data about you in the manner and for the purposes set out above.

#### Electronic marketing

We may use your e-mail address to send you electronic marketing information. You can opt out of being contacted via e-mail using the [unsubscribe](http://pages.tieto.com/UnsubscribePage.html) function in e-mails sent by Tieto.

Tieto uses third-party service providers to display advertisements on behalf of Tieto across the Internet. These service providers may use cookies to collect information about your visits to our Website in order to display ads while you are visiting other websites; this information cannot be used to identify you individually. Such information is anonymous; however, your IP address may be collected. 

#### REMARKETING

Tieto also uses 3rd party vendor re-marketing tracking cookies, including Google Adwords tracking cookie. This allows us to make special offers and continue to market our services to those who have shown interest in our service. We respect your privacy and are not collecting any identifiable information through the use of Google’s or any other 3rd party remarketing system.

#### Website analytics

This Website uses services such as Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google Inc. Data collected by cookies about your use of the Website (including your IP address) will be transmitted to and stored by Google and other website analytics service providers, on behalf of Tieto.

Tieto use website analytics for the purpose of evaluating website usage, compiling reports on website activity for Website operators and providing other services relating to website activities and internet usage.

#### Other third-party services

Our Website may contain links to other websites and “share” buttons (such as Twitter or Facebook) that are not operating on Tieto’s behalf. Such websites, service or application providers may place their own third-party cookies on users’ computers, collect data, or solicit personal information. 

Issuers of such third-party cookies have their own strict privacy policies. You should refer to any privacy policies from such websites, service or application providers to better understand how your information may be collected and used.

### How do I disable cookies?

You may block cookies by activating the setting on your browser that allows you to refuse accepting cookies. However, if you select this setting, you may be unable to access certain parts of the Website. Unless you have adjusted your browser setting so that it will refuse cookies, Tieto will issue cookies when you access our Website.

## File descriptions and contacting Tieto

If you have any questions regarding this Privacy Statement or if you are concerned about how your personal data is processed by Tieto, please send an e-mail to [webmaster@tieto.com](mailto:webmaster@tieto.com) or contact Kristina Westerlind.

File descriptions related to processing of personal data under this Website for [marketing](https://www.tieto.com/sites/default/files/files/marketing-1102510_description_of_file.pdf), [recruitment and human resources](http://www.tieto.com/sites/default/files/atoms/files/file_description_careers_recruitment.pdf) purposes are available on this page.

## Changes to the Privacy Statement

Tieto reserves the right to amend this Privacy Statement and the linked file descriptions at any time. You must review this Privacy Statement from time to time for any amendments.
